<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew Alan Green</title>
    <link>https://matthewalangreen.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matthew Alan Green</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matthewalangreen.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcoming the Extinction Burst</title>
      <link>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/welcoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 08:58:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/welcoming/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash; Read story on Medium.com. Photo by Rodion Kutsaev on Unsplash. &amp;ndash;
Elly wasn’t having it, her shrill vocalizations ensuring we were fully aware of her disapproval. Out flew Mr. Pigglesworth, followed by her blanket, pacifier, and the last shreds of her composure. We’d been warned that this day was coming, as new parents we’d done what we could to prepare.
But you can’t really prepare for how this feels, other than knowing it’s coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shouting Into the Wind</title>
      <link>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/shouting-into-the-wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/shouting-into-the-wind/</guid>
      <description>Read on Medium.com
“Seattle public schools just decided that math is racist.” She told me over a plate of almost-warm powdered eggs at our table in the back of the room. I attended the Idaho School Board Association Convention earlier this month and was told that mathematics doesn’t have culture by a frustrated school board member over breakfast one morning. She peppered me with sincere questions about how Mathematics could have anything to do with culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re the Adults in the room, it&#39;s time to act like it.</title>
      <link>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/were-the-adults-in-the-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/were-the-adults-in-the-room/</guid>
      <description>Read on Medium.com
Tim keeps the supplies in his classroom for the math department. He finds joy in being the person to anticipate and provide for our daily dry erase marker and mechanical pencil needs. Tim is a caretaker.
On a Tuesday some years ago I quietly entered his second period to grab a few black and purple dry erase markers. It had to be a Tuesday because during first period, every Tuesday, Tim would descend from the math department’s perch on the top floor, to the basement on his weekly resupply mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the Great Idaho STEM Together</title>
      <link>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/reflections-on-great-idaho-stem-together-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/reflections-on-great-idaho-stem-together-2019/</guid>
      <description>Read on Medium.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on &#34;What School Could Be&#34;</title>
      <link>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/reflections-on-what-school-could-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/reflections-on-what-school-could-be/</guid>
      <description>Read on Medium.com
I finished reading “What School Could Be” by Ted Dintersmith on our family vacation earlier this week. I needed it. He breathed life into my teaching soul as I’ve been struggling with the loss of my beloved Riverpoint Academy which despite great community support and a focus on doing better things , was closed due to budget cuts.
I’m hurting.
I left a far more progressive school district in Spokane with a long track record of innovative programs to work at RA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interview with Scott Swaaley</title>
      <link>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/an-interview-with-scott-swaaley/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/an-interview-with-scott-swaaley/</guid>
      <description>Read on Medium.com
Scott Swaaley is one of the High Tech High teachers in the film Most Likely To Succeed , from Ted Dintersmith. As I finished Dintersmith’s book: “What School Could Be” , this week I was reminded of when my colleague John Marshall and I interviewed Scott a few years back.
We first met Scott through our colleague, Riverpoint Academy’s founding teacher, Regan Drew . Regan and Scott are Allen Distinguished Educators, and their collaboration brought Scott to RA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Better Things AND Doing (Obsolete) Things Better</title>
      <link>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/doing-better-things-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewalangreen.com/posts/doing-better-things-and/</guid>
      <description>Read on Medium.com
Ted Dintersmith makes a clear and compelling call to our American education system in “ What School Could Be. ” He bemoans “doing (obsolete) things better,” in favor of “doing better things.” I had the privilege of doing better things at Riverpoint Academy (RA) for six amazing years. More on that in a moment.
I love this book. I love Dintersmith’s clarity and focus, but I think he is missing some nuance in how we go about navigating this “entrenched system” at the classroom level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matthewalangreen.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewalangreen.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Learner // I’m curious polymath. I love exploring 🧮 mathematics with others, 🎨 ⌨️ creative coding, rhetoric, functional programming, interpersonal communication, football coaching philosophy, and 🎮 ✈️ RC Airplanes. 📚 Reading: Coders / Range / The Design and Analysis Of Algorithms / Daring Fireball / Swift by Sundell / The Nature of Code. 💡 Inspired by: Seymour Papert / Charley Harper / Gever Tulley / Bees &amp;amp; Bombs / Daniel Shiffman / Saskia Freeke / FliteTest / my family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matthewalangreen.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewalangreen.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>matt at ce-consulting dot com
five zero nine seven two zero seven one two five</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>